Hitarth Bhatt

IOS DEVELOPER

 I +91 8302880263
 I I hitarthbhatt12@gmail.com
 I Portfolio
 I Github
 I Linkedin

Personal Profile

2 Years of experience in developing and designing iOS, iPadOS, and watchOS applications. I'm always passionate about developing a fast and reliable application. Throughout my carrier, I've developed applications from scratch to release, Implement enhanced features in big projects.

Skills_

Concepts Data Structures, OOPS, MVC, MVVM-C, RESTful APIs, App Store Publishing.

Language & Tools Swift, C++, Xcode, Git, JIRA, SourceTree, CocoaPods, Swift Package Manager, Charles.

Frameworks & Library SwiftUI, UIKit, Combine, Firebase, Swift Charts, Concurrency, CoreData.

Work Experience

Adobe Systems (via Hughes Systique Corporation) (PSX App)

Noida, India

iOS Developer

Apr 2023 - Present

- Valuable contributor to the growth team for a popular photo editor Adobe PSX with millions of users, maintaining an impressive 4.8 rating from around 700K users.
- Led user interaction and retention efforts, boosting engagement.
- · Engineered a captivating image editor tool selection and deselection feature with animated effects in Objc.
- Ensured seamless light and dark theme support throughout the app.
- Initiated experiments with A/B variants in different countries, using adobe analytics to elevate successful variants to global features.

Simform Solutions (AI-Health App)

Ahmedabad, India

iOS Developer

Jul 2021 - Feb 2023

- Working on Fitness application which works over Apple devices (iPad, iPhone, watchOS).
- · Working with 5 person's team in a remote environment and providing fast deliveries of new features.
- · Improved legacy code and apply MVVM architecture as well as SwiftUI framework for new features and redesigned screen.
- Refactor more than 80% watchOS screens to SwiftUI framework.
- Implement **pixel-perfect** designs provided by designer.
- Technology Stack: UIKit, SwiftUI, Networking, Concurrency, Firebase, AVFoundation, Swift Charts, etc.

Jain Fast Food (App Link)

Remote, India

iOS Developer Oct 2020 - Mar 2021

- Developed iOS application from scratch and Publish it on App Store.
- Developed Admin iOS application which monitors profits, Add and modify the client side app data.
- Used Combine Framework to ensure that the user authenticates perfectly.
- Technology Stack: SwiftUI, Firebase, Push Notification, JSON Parsing, Combine, CoreLocation, SDWebImage, etc.

Projects _____

SSLineChart (Link)

Ahmedabad, India

Open Source Project

- · Developed an open-source library exclusively for watchOS, offering the unique capability to create gradient-based line charts in Swift.
- Implemented functionality for drawing gradient elements, meeting the demand for visually appealing data representation on watchOS platforms.

Education

Arya College Of Engineering And IT

lainur India

BTech in Information Technology (7.1 CGPA)

2017 - 2021

Certificate & Achievements

Present **Leetcode**, Solved **200+** data structure and algorithm problems

Link

Dec 2019 **Udemy**, The Complete iOS App Development Bootcamp

Link

Oct 2019 University of Toronto, Introduction To Swift Programming

Link